A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, The Fund for the Advancement of Education (TFAE) files FA740
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Grant Awardees – Educational Institutions, 1947-1976; II; 92.4 Cubic Feet 77 boxes.
  - Grant Files, 1948-1976; 1; 51.6 Cubic Feet 43 boxes.; 43 boxes.
    - Smith College - Catalyst - Part-time teaching initiative - Reports, 1963-1964 (Box 35 (49596))
    - Smith College - Sabbatical of Professor Sheehan - Pierce College (Athens, Greece) - Grant 66, 1965-1967 (Box 35 (49596))
    - Smith College - Sabbatical of Professor Sheehan - Pierce College (Athens, Greece) - Report, 1967 (Box 35 (49596))
    - Social Science Research Council - Conferences on Learning and the Educational Process, 1964-1969 (Box 35 (49596))
    - Social Science Research Council - Conferences on Learning and the Educational Process - Grant 65, 1965-1969 (Box 35 (49596))
    - Social Science Research Council - Conferences on Learning and the Educational Process - Reports, 1966-1969 (Box 35 (49596))
    - South Supervisory Union - Visits to educational institutions - Grant 63, 1963-1964 (Box 35 (49596))
    - Southern California, University of - Recruitment and training of older liberal arts graduates as teachers - General data, correspondence and grant, 1953-1956 (Box 35 (49596))
    - Southern California, University of - Recruitment and training of older liberal arts graduates as teachers - Proposal, 1952-1955 (Box 35 (49596))
    - Southern California, University of - Recruitment and training of older liberal arts graduates as teachers - Publicity, 1954 (Box 35 (49596))
    - Southern California, University of - Recruitment and training of older liberal arts graduates as teachers - Reports - Progress, 1956-1960 (Box 35 (49596))
    - Southern Education Reporting Service (SERS) - Equal education - Bi-racial - Board of Directors meeting (March 18, 1956), 1956-1957 (Box 35 (49596))
    - Southern Education Reporting Service (SERS) - Equal education - Bi-racial - Board of Directors meeting (March 9, 1958) (Box 35 (49596))
    - Southern Education Reporting Service (SERS) - Equal education - Bi-racial - Board of Directors meeting (March 15, 1959) [Photograph] (Box 35 (49596))
      - [B+W photograph], 2014.015.027; Still Image
    - Southern Education Reporting Service (SERS) - Equal education - Bi-racial - Board of Directors meeting (March 27, 1960) (Box 35 (49596))
    - Southern Education Reporting Service (SERS) - Equal education - Bi-racial - Board of Directors - Meetings and minutes, 1954 (Box 35 (49596))
    - Southern Education Reporting Service (SERS) - Equal education - Bi-racial - Board of Directors - Meetings and minutes, 1955-1957 (Box 35 (49596))
    - Southern Education Reporting Service (SERS) - Equal education - Bi-racial - Board of Directors - Meetings and minutes, 1956-1957 (Box 35 (49596))
    - Southern Education Reporting Service (SERS) - Equal education - Bi-racial - Budget, 1954-1956 (Box 35 (49596))
    - Southern Education Reporting Service (SERS) - Equal education - Bi-racial - General correspondence and data, 1954-1962 (Box 35 (49596))
    - Southern Education Reporting Service (SERS) - Equal education - Bi-racial - Grants, 1954 (Box 35 (49596))
    - Southern Education Reporting Service (SERS) - Equal education - Bi-racial - Grants, 1955-1958 (Box 35 (49596))
    - Southern Education Reporting Service (SERS) - Equal education - Bi-racial - Press releases and clippings, 1954-1958 (Box 35 (49596))
    - Southern Education Reporting Service (SERS) - Equal education - Bi-racial - Press releases and clippings [Photograph], 1955-1960 (Box 35 (49596))
      - [B+W photograph], 2014.015.028; Still Image
    - Southern Education Reporting Service (SERS) - Equal education - Bi-racial - Publicity - Book, "With All Deliberate Speed - Segregation-Desegregation in Southern Schools", 1957 (Box 35 (49596))
      - With All Deliberate Speed: Segregation-Desegregation in Southern Schools, 2014.015.018; Published Material
    - Southern Education Reporting Service (SERS) - Equal education - Bi-racial - Reports, 1955 (Box 36 (49597))
    - Southern Education Reporting Service (SERS) - Equal education - Bi-racial - Reports - Segregation and desegregation in Southern schools and colleges, 1956 (Box 36 (49597))
    - Southern Education Reporting Service (SERS) - Equal education - Bi-racial - Reports to Board of Directors, 1954-1960 (Box 36 (49597))
    - Southern Education Reporting Service (SERS) - Equal education - Bi-racial - Report to Weiss, 1955 (Box 36 (49597))
    - Southern Education Reporting Service (SERS) - Equal education - Bi-racial - Requests, Analysis of - Southern School News, 1954 (Box 36 (49597))
    - Southern Education Reporting Service (SERS) - Equal education - Bi-racial - Statistical summary, 1957-1961 (Box 36 (49597))
    - Southern Education Reporting Service (SERS) - Equal education - Bi-racial - Updating Ashmore data - Grant and report, 1958 (Box 36 (49597))
    - Southern Education Reporting Service (SERS) - Equal education - Bi-racial - Updating Ashmore data - Grant - Supplementary, 1959 (Box 36 (49597))
    - Southern Association of Colleges and Schools - Grant 66, 1966-1967 (Box 36 (49597))
    - Southern Association of Colleges and Schools - Reports, 1966-1967 (Box 36 (49597))
    - Southern Regional Council, Inc. - Grant 66, 1966 (Box 36 (49597))
    - Southern Regional Council, Inc. - Reports, 1966-1967 (Box 36 (49597))
    - Southern Teaching Program, Inc. - Recruitment of Southern teachers - Grant 605, 1967-1968 (Box 36 (49597))
    - Southern Teaching Program, Inc. - Recruitment of Southern teachers - Reports, 1967-1968 (Box 36 (49597))
    - Spring Arbor College - Better utilization of financing control - Grant 63, 1963 (Box 36 (49597))
    - Springfield College - Efficiency of liberal arts curriculum - General data, 1960 (Box 36 (49597))
    - Springfield College - Efficiency of liberal arts curriculum - Grant 60, 1960 (Box 36 (49597))
    - Springfield College - Efficiency of liberal arts curriculum - Reports, 1962 (Box 36 (49597))
    - Springfield College - Teacher preparation summer programs - Grant 60, 1960 (Box 36 (49597))
    - Springfield College - Teacher preparation summer programs - Reports, 1961-1962 (Box 36 (49597))
    - Spring Hill College - Summer workshop in human relations - Grant 63, 1963-1966 (Box 36 (49597))
    - Spring Hill College - Summer workshop in human relations - Reports [Photograph], 1964 (Box 36 (49597))
      - [Untitled], 2014.015.019; Still Image (Box SF2)
    - Stanford University - Electronic data processing for flexible scheduling project (secondary schools) - Grant 61, 1960-1961 (Box 36 (49597))
    - Stanford University - Electronic data processing for flexible scheduling project (secondary schools) - Reports, 1961-1963 (Box 36 (49597))
    - Stanford University - Electronic data processing for university decision making - Grant 56, 1956 (Box 36 (49597))
    - Stanford University - Electronic data processing for university decision making - Grant 57 - Supplementary, 1956-1957 (Box 36 (49597))
    - Stanford University - Electronic data processing for university decision making - Reports, 1959-1960 (Box 36 (49597))
    - Stanford University - Gifted students - General data and grant, 1955-1957 (Box 36 (49597))
    - Stanford University - Gifted students - Histories of gifted subjects, 1956-1957 (Box 36 (49597))
    - Stanford University - Production of two manuscripts on higher education - Grant, 1961-1963 (Box 36 (49597))
    - Stanford University - School schedule system project (Phase III), 1965-1968 (Box 36 (49597))
    - Stanford University - School schedule system project (Phase III) - Grant 65, 1965-1967 (Box 36 (49597))
    - Stanford University - School schedule system project (Phase III) - Reports, 1966-1967 (Box 36 (49597))
    - Stanford University - Inter-departmental graduate program - Grant, 1952-1953 (Box 36 (49597))
    - Stanford University - Inter-departmental graduate program - Grant, 1959-1960 (Box 36 (49597))
    - Stanford University - Inter-departmental graduate program - Planning, 1952 (Box 36 (49597))
    - Stanford University - Inter-departmental graduate program - Reports - Progress, 1955-1965 (Box 36 (49597))
    - Stanford University - Inter-departmental graduate program, 1956-1957 (Box 36 (49597))
    - Stephens College - Telecture humanities and science - Grants, 1963-1964 (Box 36 (49597))
    - Stephens College - Telecture humanities and science - Reports, 1965-1966 (Box 36 (49597))
    - Stephens College - College house plan - Grant, 1960-1965 (Box 36 (49597))
    - Stephens College - College house plan - Report, 1960-1966 (Box 36 (49597))
      - [Untitled], 2014.015.020; Still Image (Box SF2)
    - Temple University - Teacher education program - Evaluation, 1954-1955 (Box 36 (49597))
    - Temple University - Teacher education program - Planning, 1955 (Box 36 (49597))
    - Temple University - Teacher education program - Reports - Progress - Studies 1, 2, 1955 (Box 36 (49597))
    - Temple University - Teacher education program - Summary of project - Studies 1, 2, 1955 (Box 36 (49597))
    - Tennessee, University of - Grant 66, 1965-1967 (Box 36 (49597))
    - Tennessee, University of - Reports, 1966-1967 (Box 36 (49597))
    - Texas Education Agency - Utilization and preparation of teachers and school property through television - General data, 1956 (Box 37 (49598))
    - Texas Education Agency - Utilization and preparation of teachers and school property through television - Grant, 1958-1959 (Box 37 (49598))
    - Texas Education Agency - Utilization and preparation of teachers and school property through television - Grants and proposal, 1956-1957 (Box 37 (49598))
    - Texas Education Agency - Utilization and preparation of teachers and school property through television - Report, 1956-1958 (Box 37 (49598))
    - Texas Education Agency - Utilization and preparation of teachers and school property through television - Reports, 1956-1959 (Box 37 (49598))
    - Texas Educational Foundation, Inc. - Grant 66, 1966-1967 (Box 37 (49598))
    - Texas Southern University - Grant 63, 1963-1967 (Box 37 (49598))
    - Texas Southern University - Publicity, 1963 (Box 37 (49598))
    - Texas Southern University - Reports, 1964 (Box 37 (49598))
    - Texas, University of - Accelerated curriculum - Grant, 1956-1957 (Box 37 (49598))
    - Texas, University of - Accelerated curriculum - Grant, 1958-1960 (Box 37 (49598))
    - Texas, University of - Accelerated curriculum - Public relations and publicity - Press releases, 1958-1959 (Box 37 (49598))
    - Texas, University of - Accelerated curriculum - Reports, 1956-1958 (Box 37 (49598))
    - Texas, University of - Television - General data, 1957-1959 (Box 37 (49598))
    - Texas, University of - Television - Grant, 1959-1962 (Box 37 (49598))
    - Texas, University of - Television - Publicity, 1959 (Box 37 (49598))
    - Thayer Academy - Accelerated curriculum - General data, 1957 (Box 37 (49598))
    - Thayer Academy - Accelerated curriculum - Grant, 1958-1959 (Box 37 (49598))
    - Thayer Academy - Accelerated curriculum - Publicity, 1958 (Box 37 (49598))
    - Thayer Academy - Accelerated curriculum - Reports, 1958-1960 (Box 37 (49598))
    - Tougaloo College - Space utilization study - Grant, 1964 (Box 37 (49598))
    - Tougaloo College - Space utilization study - Reports, 1965-1966 (Box 37 (49598))
    - Tougaloo College - Support of selected areas to strengthen College's program - Grant, 1964-1965 (Box 37 (49598))
    - Tougaloo College - Support of selected areas to strengthen College's program - Reports, 1964-1965 (Box 37 (49598))
    - Trenton Public Schools - Travel and study - Attachments, 1965 (Box 37 (49598))
    - Trenton Public Schools - Travel and study - Grant, 1966 (Box 37 (49598))
    - Trenton Public Schools - Travel and study - Reports, 1965 (Box 37 (49598))
    - Trinity College - Advanced Placement - General data, 1960-1962 (Box 37 (49598))
    - Trinity College - Advanced Placement - Grant, 1959-1960 (Box 37 (49598))
    - Trinity College - Advanced Placement - Publicity, 1962 (Box 37 (49598))
    - Trinity College - Advanced Placement - Report, 1960 (Box 37 (49598))
    - Trinity School - Elementary reading program - General correspondence, 1963-1964 (Box 37 (49598))
    - Trinity School - Elementary reading program - Grant, 1963-1968 (Box 37 (49598))
    - Trinity School - Elementary reading program - Reports, 1965-1968 (Box 37 (49598))
    - Union Free School District #2 - Irvington - Travel and study - Grant, 1965-1966 (Box 37 (49598))
    - Union Free School District #2 - Irvington - Travel and study - Reports, 1965 (Box 37 (49598))
    - United Nations International School - Program development - Grant, 1965-1971 (Box 37 (49598))
    - United Nations International School - Program development - Reports, 1966-1970 (Box 37 (49598))
    - United Nations International School - Program development - Report [Photographs], 1971 (Box 37 (49598))
      - [Untitled], 2014.015.021; Still Image (Box SF2)
    - United Nations International School - Space utilization study - Grant, 1964-1965 (Box 37 (49598))
    - United Nations International School - Space utilization study - Reports, 1965 (Box 37 (49598))
    - United Nations International School - General data, 1955-1960 (Box 37 (49598))
    - United Nations International School - Grants, 1955-1960 (Box 37 (49598))
    - United Nations International School - Programs, 1950-1955 (Box 37 (49598))
    - United Nations International School - Reports, visits, 1956-1957 (Box 37 (49598))
    - United Nations International School - Reports - Progress, 1955-1960 (Box 37 (49598))
    - U.S. National Student Association - Grant, 1966-1967 (Box 38 (49599))
    - U.S. National Student Association - Reports, 1966-1967 (Box 38 (49599))
    - University Center in Virginia, Inc. - Toynbee evaluation - General correspondence, 1959 (Box 38 (49599))
    - University Center in Virginia, Inc. - Toynbee evaluation - General data, 1959 (Box 38 (49599))
    - University Center in Virginia, Inc. - Toynbee evaluation - Grant, 1959 (Box 38 (49599))
    - University Center in Virginia, Inc. - Toynbee evaluation - Report, 1960 (Box 38 (49599))
    - University Council for Educational Administration - Training school administrators - General correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 38 (49599))
    - University Council for Educational Administration - Training school administrators - General data, 1961 (Box 38 (49599))
    - University Council for Educational Administration - Training school administrators - Grant, 1958-1962 (Box 38 (49599))
    - University Council for Educational Administration - Training school administrators - Reports, 1961-1962 (Box 38 (49599))
    - University Council for Educational Administration - Training school administrators - Report - Book, "Preparing Administrators: New Perspectives", 1962 (Box 38 (49599))
    - W. E. Upjohn Unemployment Trustee Corporation - Study of industrial advisory committees - Grant, 1964-1967 (Box 38 (49599))
    - W. E. Upjohn Unemployment Trustee Corporation - Study of industrial advisory committees - Reports, 1964-1966 (Box 38 (49599))
    - W. E. Upjohn Unemployment Trustee Corporation - Study of industrial advisory committees - Report, Volume I, 1966 (Box 38 (49599))
    - W. E. Upjohn Unemployment Trustee Corporation - Study of industrial advisory committees - Report, Volume II, 1966 (Box 38 (49599))
    - Upland College - Improvement in curricula - Mid-year seminar - General correspondence, 1960-1962 (Box 38 (49599))
    - Upland College - Improvement in curricula - Mid-year seminar - General data, 1961 (Box 38 (49599))
    - Upland College - Improvement in curricula - Mid-year seminar - Grant, 1960 (Box 38 (49599))
    - Upland College - Improvement in curricula - Mid-year seminar - Grant - Supplementary, 1961-1962 (Box 38 (49599))
    - Upland College - Improvement in curricula - Mid-year seminar - Reports, 1961-1962 (Box 38 (49599))
    - Utah State Board of Education - Grant, 1966-1967 (Box 38 (49599))
    - Utah State Board of Education - Report, 1961 (Box 38 (49599))
    - Utah State Board of Education - Reports, 1964-1966 (Box 38 (49599))
    - Utah State Board of Education - American Values Project - Report, 1965 (Box 39 (49600))
    - Utah State Board of Education - American Values Project - Report, 1965 (Box 39 (49600))
    - Utah, Department of Public Instruction - Advanced Placement - Grant, 1961-1962 (Box 39 (49600))
    - Utah, Department of Public Instruction - Advanced Placement - Reports, 1962-1964 (Box 39 (49600))
    - Utah, Department of Public Instruction - School improvement program - Grant, 1961-1967 (Box 39 (49600))
    - Utah, Department of Public Instruction - School improvement program - Reports, 1966 (Box 39 (49600))
    - Vanderbilt University - Financing medical education - General correspondence and grant, 1955-1956 (Box 39 (49600))
    - Vanderbilt University - Financing medical education - Meeting (June 12, 1952) (Box 39 (49600))
    - Vanderbilt University - Financing medical education - Report - Progress, 1955 (Box 39 (49600))
    - Vanderbilt University - Inter-departmental graduate program - General data, 1958 (Box 39 (49600))
    - Vanderbilt University - Inter-departmental graduate program - Grant, 1953-1956 (Box 39 (49600))
    - Vanderbilt University - Inter-departmental graduate program - Publicity, 1955 (Box 39 (49600))
    - Vanderbilt University - Inter-departmental graduate program - Reports, 1955-1957 (Box 39 (49600))
    - Vanderbilt University - General data, 1958-1959 (Box 39 (49600))
    - Vanderbilt University - Utilization of college teaching resources - Independent study - Grant, 1959 (Box 39 (49600))
    - Vassar College - Improvement in curricula - Grant, 1958 (Box 39 (49600))
    - Vassar College - Improvement in curricula - Report [Confidential], 1958 (Box 39 (49600))
    - Vassar College - Study based on Ruml report - Grant, 1960 (Box 39 (49600))
    - Vassar College - Study based on Ruml report - Reports, 1960-1962 (Box 39 (49600))
    - Vassar College - Internship program, 1953-1955 (Box 39 (49600))
    - Vassar College - Internship program - Grants, 1953-1954 (Box 39 (49600))
    - Vassar College - Internship program - Reports, 1953-1954 (Box 39 (49600))
    - Volunteers in Service to America (VISTA) - Attachments [Photograph], 1966 (Box 39 (49600))
    - Volunteers in Service to America (VISTA) - Grant, 1966-1967 (Box 39 (49600))
    - Volunteers in Service to America (VISTA) - Reports, 1966-1967 (Box 39 (49600))
    - Wabash College - Experimental curriculum (physics and chemistry) - Classroom material (1/2), 1955-1956 (Box 39 (49600))
    - Wabash College - Experimental curriculum (physics and chemistry) - Classroom material (2/2), 1955-1956 (Box 39 (49600))
    - Wabash College - Experimental curriculum (physics and chemistry) - General correspondence, 1955-1956 (Box 39 (49600))
    - Wabash College - Experimental curriculum (physics and chemistry) - Grant, 1954-1956 (Box 39 (49600))
    - Wabash College - Experimental curriculum (physics and chemistry) - Questionnaire results, 1955 (Box 39 (49600))
    - Waco Independent School District - Administrative organization - General correspondence and grant proposal, 1956-1957 (Box 39 (49600))
    - Waco Independent School District - Administrative organization - Reports, 1957 (Box 39 (49600))
    - Wake Forest College - Grant, 1959 (Box 39 (49600))
    - Washington County Board of Education - Advanced Placement - General correspondence, 1961 (Box 39 (49600))
    - Washington County Board of Education - Advanced Placement - General data, 1959 (Box 39 (49600))
    - Washington County Board of Education - Advanced Placement - Grant, 1959 (Box 39 (49600))
    - Washington County Board of Education - Advanced Placement - Publicity, 1960 (Box 39 (49600))
    - Washington County Board of Education - Advanced Placement - Report, 1961 (Box 39 (49600))
    - Washington and Lee University - Toynbee lectures and film - Grant, 1957-1958 (Box 39 (49600))
    - Washington and Lee University - Toynbee lectures and film - Publicity, 1958-1959 (Box 39 (49600))
    - Water and Sewarage Technical School - Work-study program - Attachments, 1961-1967 (Box 39 (49600))
    - Water and Sewarage Technical School - Work-study program - Grant, 1964-1969 (Box 39 (49600))
    - Water and Sewarage Technical School - Work-study program - Reports, 1965-1968 (Box 39 (49600))
    - Water and Sewarage Technical School - Grant, 1966-1968 (Box 39 (49600))
    - Water and Sewarage Technical School - Reports, 1967-1968 (Box 39 (49600))
    - Wilberforce University - Cooperative Work-Study Program - Attachments, 1965 (Box 40 (49601))
    - Wilberforce University - Cooperative Work-Study Program - Reports, 1965-1967 (Box 40 (49601))
    - Wilberforce University - Cooperative Work-Study Program - Grant, 1965-1968 (Box 40 (49601))
    - Willamette University - Faculty leaves and sabbaticals - Grant, 1965-1967 (Box 40 (49601))
    - Willamette University - Faculty leaves and sabbaticals - Reports, 1966-1967 (Box 40 (49601))
    - Williams College - Faculty children's tuition exchange - Attachments, 1954-1955 (Box 40 (49601))
    - Williams College - Faculty children's tuition exchange - Attachments [Confidential], 1955 (Box 40 (49601))
    - Williams College - Faculty children's tuition exchange - General data, 1955-1965 (Box 40 (49601))
    - Williams College - Faculty children's tuition exchange - Grant, 1954-1965 (Box 40 (49601))
    - Williams College - Internship program - Grant, 1954-1955 (Box 40 (49601))
    - Williams College - Roper Public Opinion Research Center - Grant [Photographs], 1958-1961 (Box 40 (49601))
      - [Untitled], 2014.015.022; Still Image (Box SF2)
    - Wilmington College - Attachments, 1960 (Box 40 (49601))
    - Wilmington College - Grant, 1965-1967 (Box 40 (49601))
    - Wilmington College - Reports, 1966-1967 (Box 40 (49601))
    - Wilson College - Grant and financials, 1954-1957 (Box 40 (49601))
    - Wilson College - Reports - Progress, 1955-1960 (Box 40 (49601))
    - Wilson College - Visit, 1954-1957 (Box 40 (49601))
    - Winneteka Public Schools - Learning Lab - School improvement - Attachments, 1960-1963 (Box 40 (49601))
    - Winneteka Public Schools - Learning Lab - School improvement - Grant, 1962-1966 (Box 40 (49601))
    - Winneteka Public Schools - Learning Lab - School improvement - Reports, 1964-1966 (Box 40 (49601))
    - Wisconsin State Department of Public Instruction - School Improvement - Attachments, 1964-1965 (Box 40 (49601))
    - Wisconsin State Department of Public Instruction - School Improvement - Grant, 1962-1968 (Box 40 (49601))
    - Wisconsin State Department of Public Instruction - School Improvement - Reports, 1963-1967 (Box 40 (49601))
    - Wisconsin, Universtiy of - Breakthrough - Graduate school - General data, 1959 (Box 40 (49601))
    - Wisconsin, Universtiy of - Breakthrough - Graduate school - Grant, 1958-1959 (Box 40 (49601))
    - Wisconsin, Universtiy of - Breakthrough - Graduate school - Reports, 1959 (Box 40 (49601))
    - Wisconsin, Universtiy of - Breakthrough - School of Education - General correspondence, 1960 (Box 40 (49601))
    - Wisconsin, Universtiy of - Breakthrough - School of Education - General data, 1958-1960 (Box 40 (49601))
    - Wisconsin, Universtiy of - Breakthrough - School of Education - Grant, 1958-1970 (Box 40 (49601))
    - Wisconsin, Universtiy of - Breakthrough - School of Education - Publicity, 1959-1960 (Box 40 (49601))
    - Wisconsin, Universtiy of - Breakthrough - School of Education - Report, 1958-1959 (Box 40 (49601))
    - Wisconsin, Universtiy of - Institutional relations - Grant, 1960-1961 (Box 40 (49601))
    - Wisconsin, Universtiy of - Institutional relations - Report, 1960 (Box 40 (49601))